Archer, I don't believe it. You—
You once asked me this, Saber:
"Have you no pride as a hero?"
Of course I don't.
All I have left is foolish regrets.
The thing is, Saber...
I should never have become a hero.
I suggest you stand aside, King of Knights.
If you exert yourself with no Master, you will quickly disappear.
Emiya Shirou is no longer a Master.
Aiding him will not help your wish come true.
I swore that I would be the sword that protected him.
Even without our contract, that pledge remains unchanged.
I see.
In that case...
The Beginning of the Circle
Die here, along with your false master.
Oh?
I expected you to cower a bit longer.
Shut up!
You're fighting the wrong person!
Your imitation is close enough to effectively be the real thing.
But can your body handle that level of magical exertion?
Using magic beyond your ability will destroy you.
Or did you honestly think you would succeed?
That if you stubbornly kept trying,
your ideal self would come within your grasp?
Archer...
That is as far as Emiya Shirou can go.
A fitting end for a fool who constantly tried to do the impossible.
I hereby propose.
Your fealty shall be mine, and my fate shall be yours.
If you heed the Grail's call and obey my will and reason...
then obey me!
Do so, and I shall entrust my fate to your sword!
On my honor as Saber, I accept your oath.
I accept you as my Master, Rin.
What will it be, Saber?
Now that you've made a contract with Rin,
your ties with Emiya Shirou have been well and truly severed.
Weren't you listening, Archer?
My pledge to Shirou stands.
And what will you do?
Surely you do not think you can defeat me as I am now.
How confident you've become
after simply having your mana restored.
It's over, Archer.
Earlier, you voiced concern for my wellbeing,
but now I could say the same to you.
You have nothing to anchor you to this world.
And with no means of supplying yourself with mana, what can you do?
Servants of the Archer class
have the ability to act independently.
I think I can last two days or so without a Master.
More than enough time to put down that boy.
Ridiculous. Do you still refuse to let go of that obsession?
Are you saying your wish was never the Holy Grail,
but killing Shirou?
Archer, your wish is misguided.
Misguided, is it?
You took the words out of my mouth, Saber.
How long will you cling to your own misguided wish?
Instead of lamenting your failure to leave a legacy,
why can't you look back and accept that you did all you could?
I am an archer.
I was never meant to fight using swords.
Though admittedly...
My bow is just as much a borrowed forgery.
I'm saying that I will show you my true nature.
That is the greatest recompense that I can offer you.
I am the bone of my sword.
Stop, Archer!
I do not wish to...
Unknown to Death.
Nor known to Life.
Saber, one day someone will appear who will free you.
But the sole objective of my current self is to kill Emiya Shirou.
If you try to stand in my way,
this world will not show mercy, even to you.
Unlimited...
Blade Works!
A Reality Marble?
A forbidden spell that causes the caster's inner world to manifest itself and encroach on reality.
Which means that you aren't a swordsman or a bowman.
Correct.
Before I became a Heroic Spirit, I was a mage in life.
Then what is your Noble Phantasm, Archer?
I owned neither a holy sword nor a demonic one.
All I have is this world.
If a Noble Phantasm is a Heroic Spirit's symbol,
then this Reality Marble is my Noble Phantasm.
It reproduces and stores any weapon whose original I've seen.
That is my ability as a Heroic Spirit.
Then this...
You're saying this desolate wasteland
is the culmination of your life's efforts, Archer?
You don't mince words.
Care to test it, Saber?
I'll faithfully replicate that holy sword of yours.
My holy sword?
Yes. It is a projection that's certain to end in my destruction,
but I can produce a convincing replica.
It should last long enough to take you with me.
However, when two holy swords clash,
who can say whether any humans in the vicinity will survive?
That son of a...
Feel free to dodge them.
But if you do, you will doom the man behind you.
Shirou?!
If the rules and principles of all the copying I've done so far are right...
Trace...
on!
Faster.
Better.
Stronger.
I understand the structure.
I'm sick of
your crap!
The Reality Marble's gone?
Why?
Archer, what do you think you're...
Tohsaka!
Where are you going, Archer?
Back to the drawing board.
After that gambit, I'm out of mana.
I'm in no state to take you on at full strength.
This is simply my insurance policy.
If you value your Master's life, I suggest you stay out of this, Saber.
My objective is that boy's—
The forest outside of town.
What?
There's a castle there that's empty now.
Shirou?
You want to give me a piece of your mind?
Fine, let's hear it.
There are things I want to say to you too.
True, we won't be interrupted at that castle.
I like your resolve, Emiya Shirou.
Go to hell.
And don't you dare hurt Tohsaka.
I'll kill you!
I'll guarantee her safety for one day.
Be quick, though.
I won't last longer than two days without a Master.
If I can't kill you by that time,
I might just dismember my hostage out of spite.
Shirou!
You're being reckless.
You're too inexperienced to attempt the same projections as Archer.
Sorry, Saber.
I let Tohsaka get captured.
Right now, you are in more danger than she is.
Let me worry about Rin.
You should return home and rest.
Looks like you took care of business, kid.
Hold on, Saber.
He helped us.
Are you saying that Lancer assisted you, Shirou?
Yeah, he did.
So try not to fight him for now, okay?
Why, Lancer?
Do you have some ulterior motive in helping Shirou and Rin?
Of course I do.
You think I'd help my opponents if there was nothing in it for me?
I understand.
Meaning that you've gotten what you wanted.
Then begone.
I won't fight you now, either.
Hey. It appears things didn't go entirely according to plan.
What happened in there, kid?
Tohsaka's been abducted by Archer.
This hill is his world—
the ultimate result of his unending quest to help people.
It seemed like he'd embraced this landscape
and died with a smile, saying he was satisfied.
Seriously? How stupid is that?
Anyway, that made me really angry.
He worked and worked, striving for greatness
even though he was ordinary,
finally achieving his miracle as he bled.
So it'd be unthinkable for him not to find his happiness.
If he made lots of people happy,
he should become at least as happy as those people combined.
However, that wasn't the reward he received.
Instead, all he got
was his exploitation as a Guardian, even after his death.
Why did I never put it together?
Servants are summoned from every age.
Heroic Spirits can be summoned from the past, the present, or even the distant future.
Nothing says a Servant couldn't be summoned
into the time when he lived, to the city in which he once lived.
That thought frustrates me so much.
Because neither one will be saved.
Neither the one looking at his past self
nor the one looking at his future self.
All they can do is mourn what they've become.
I already know how it will end
for that fool who lives to help others.
He voluntarily sacrificed his afterlife.
If he could keep saving people, even after death,
he could ask no more.
Because of his powerlessness, he failed to save people in life.
So, thinking that he could avert
all kinds of tragedies as a Heroic Spirit,
he sold the peace he would have found in death,
believing with all his heart
that he could save tens of thousands more lives.
But even that hope was betrayed.
Only one thing can be said about him:
that he has been constantly betrayed by everything around him.
And at the very, very end,
he was betrayed even by the one ideal in which he believed.
What are you trying to pull, Archer?
Shirou would have come after you whether I was here or not.
You should know that better than anyone.
I suppose you're right.
But it would be inconvenient to have you in the way.
I see.
Then you intend to kill Shirou, no matter what, don't you?
Yes, that naïve boy should be put down before it's too late.
I don't need you to tell me that Shirou is naïve.
But even so, I think his naïveté is sweet.
That's how he ought to be.
It gives me hope that he has a place in this world.
But what about you?
After all you've done,
did you decide that waving self-indulgent idealism in people's faces is wrong?
After fighting for others time and time again,
being betrayed time and time again,
being forced to clean up other people's messes
time and time again...
Did you...
Did you lose your faith in humanity,
Archer?
I am the bone of my sword...
That's the incantation you were given
after you became a Heroic Spirit, right?
What the hell?
It's basically a curse.
I can't come to terms with one single thing about your life.
Not your idiotic way of living,
nor the people around you who didn't set you straight.
Try as I might,
I just can't come to terms with it.
What a surprise, Tohsaka!
I was skeptical, but you really are here.
Shinji?
Visitors?
I came here because I thought we wouldn't be disturbed.
Hey, now.
No funny business, Archer.
I'm not interested in you.
In fact, I should warn you: you're outmatched.
You're scared, aren't you, Archer?
My Servant dispatched Berserker without breaking a sweat.
I don't blame you for being scared of—
You want Rin, Matou Shinji?
Of course I do.
Then wait until my business is concluded.
Once I've finished Emiya Shirou, she's all yours.
If you won't agree to those terms,
I'll eliminate both you and your Servant.
Oh?
Hold on, Gilgamesh.
It's fine. He says he'll give her to us, so let's go along.
We'll keep Tohsaka safe until he's dealt with Emiya, okay?
Which means...
She's already as good as mine, right?
So I can do anything I want to her, right?
My agreement with Emiya Shirou was that she'd remain unharmed.
But that expires at dawn.
Once the deadline has passed, do as you will.
Did you hear that, Tohsaka?
Your Servant's willing to sell out his Master!
Faker.
Have you awoken,
Shirou?
Yeah, the fatigue's gone, and so is my headache.
My mana's still pretty depleted,
but it doesn't seem like my magic circuits were burned out.
Shirou...
Rin is my Master.
Rescuing her is my duty.
I will stop Archer, so you—
That's backwards, Saber.
I'll handle the fight with Archer.
You cannot, Shirou.
Archer is your...
I know.
I've probably known who he was since the moment I met him.
All the more reason why I can't stand for what he's done.
I have to be the one to settle things with him.
Please. Let me fight Archer.
And when it happens, I want you to stay out of it, no matter what.
If that is your wish, I shall abide by it.
I swore that I would be your shield.
As such, I shall watch over you to the very end.
Thanks, Saber.
I'm surprised you don't have better things to do.
I've changed my mind.
The little lady's in trouble, right?
So let me tag along a bit longer.
I couldn't sleep at night if I left her.
What manner of magic did you and Rin use
to bring him over to your side?
Ryuudou Temple, Miyama. Fifty-three unconscious.
All male.
Low blood pressure, labored breathing.
Identical symptoms to the other coma patients.
Send thirty-one to Shinto's general hospital, fifteen to the central hospital,
and the rest to the community hospital.
Wasn't it my Master's credo to never reveal themselves?
There can't be two of those pendants.
Why would your own ideal reject you?
I'm leaving this fight before you.
THE ANSWER
Idealism's End
Next Time
In any event, you have no future.